

Contact

Personal website

✓ daniel.ordonez@upc.edu

+34 603 63 96 62

in linkedin.com/in/danfoa

github.com/Danfoa

Profile

I am a Colombian engineer with a strong passion for Robotics and Computer Science. My research interests are machine learning and optimal control specially applied to legged locomotion, dexterous manipulation, reinforcement learning, and most applications aimed to close the performance gap between animals and robotic systems. Born in: 1995

LANGUAGES

Spanish English German

Mother Tongue C1 (TOEFL) Intermediate - B2

Programming

ADVANCED







INTERMEDIATE





Software & OSs

ADVANCED











INTERMEDIATE





Crocoddyl



Dr. Francesc Moreno-Noguer

BARCELONA TECH Tel: (+34) 34 934010775 fmoreno@iri.upc.edu

Dr. Mario Martin

BARCELONA TECH Tel: (+34) 93 413 7883 mmartin@cs.upc.edu

Dr. Carl-Helmut Coulon

INVITE GMBH Tel: (+49) 214 312 03125 carl-helmut.coulon@bayer.com

Daniel Felipe Ordoñez Apraez

M.Sc. Artificial Intelligence - B.Sc. Mechatronics Engineering

EDUCATION

2019-2021 Barcelona

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya - Barclona Tech

M.Sc. in Artificial Intelligence Spain 💡

Thesis: Learning to run naturally: guiding policies with the Spring-Loaded In-

verted Pendulum

2013-2018 Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Bogota B.Sc. in Mechatronics Engineering

Exchange semester: Informatics faculty of the Technique University of Munich

EXPERIENCE

Colombia 💡

2021-Present 2019-2020

Barcelona Spain **Q**

Institut de Robòtica i Informàtica Industrial (IRI-CSIC)

ASSISTANT RESEARCHER STUDENT RESEARCHER

Research Projects: Learning realistic legged locomotion with Reinforcement Learning techniques and template dynamical models - Interactive Perception-Action-Learning for Modelling Objects (IPALM) - Human hand motion forecasting and pose discretization

INVITE GmbH research center (TU Dortmund & Bayer Technology Services)

2018-2019 2017-2018

Cologne Germany 9 JUNIOR RESEARCH ASSISTANT **ROBOTICS INTERN**

Research project: Manipulation of plastic bags using a two-arm robot with 3D vision and force feedback.

- Project Presentation Video
- EP-Patent: Autonomous Drum and Inliner Handling Expected resolution 2022
- Final work certificate

2016-2017

Bogotá Colombia 💡 Busescool SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Developed front and back-end of administrative tools that allowed the control and monitoring of Busescool's realtime database and services

Mar-Dec 2016

Universidad Nacional de Colombia Bogotá **ENGINEERING FACULTY TUTOR** Colombia 💡

Courses tutored: - Data structures and algorithms - Numerical methods - Control theory - Object-oriented programming - Basic programming

Publications - Patents

- Ordonez-Apraez, Daniel Agudo, Antonio Moreno, Francesc Martin, Mario. An Adaptable Approach to Learn Realistic Legged Locomotion without Examples. Accepted to ICRA 2022
- Ordonez-Apraez, Daniel. INVITE GmbH., Bayer A.G. Autonomous Drum and Inliner Handling. Pending European Patent, expected resolution 2022.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Implementation of DeepMind's Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning model of commonpool resource appropriation
- Measuring Parkinson's disease progression
- Developed approach for The Semantic Evaluation (SemEval) challenge 2012
- Protein evolution/structure prediction Design of custom permutation invariant CNN layers targeted at processing protein's Multiple Sequence Alignments
- Transition INVITE's robotics research platform to ROS.
- Mechanic, electronic and control design of a Micromouse
- Mechanic and control design of a two-DoF RP robot
- Control design of a 1-DoF air propelled system experimenting with different robust control techniques (H_{∞} , Slide Mode Control and Adaptive control)

Awards

2019 Top 1% score on the Colombian Saber-Pro national exam, which evaluates all students near graduation of a higher education's degree

2019 Selected to the Colombian COLFUTURO's recruitment of talent program and awarded scholarship/loan for higher education

2015 University tuition exception

TEACHING AND INVITED LECTURES

Jan-Feb 3D-Vision Laboratory

2022 M.Sc. IN COMPUTER VISION - UNIVERSITAT AUTÒNOMA DE BARCELONA

Barcelona Main Lecturer: Prof. Dr. Gloria Haro

Spain 😯

Dec 2021 Introduction to AI - On Applications to Speech-language pathology

Barcelona Bs in Speech-language pathology - Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona

Spain ♥ Single Guest Lecture

Main Lecturer: Prof. Paula Resina

PRESENTATIONS

Dec 2021Barcelona
Spain ♥

An Adaptable Approach to Learn Realistic Legged Locomotion without Examples

POSTER AT DEEP LEARNING BARCELONA SYMPOSIUM